<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
    or more contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file
    distributed with this work for additional information
    regarding copyright ownership. The ASF licenses this file
    to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
    "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
    with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
    software distributed under the License is distributed on an
    "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
    KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the
    specific language governing permissions and limitations
    under the License.
-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Website</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://james.apache.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://james.apache.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 17:15:39 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 17:15:39 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.5.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apache James developers are pleased to announce James server 3.5.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;announcements&quot;&gt;Announcements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distributed-james-guice-product-beta&quot;&gt;Distributed James guice product beta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, recent work of the Apache James project did lead to a James product that leverages a distributed mail server,
using storage technologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cassandra.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Cassandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elastic.co/elasticsearch/&quot;&gt;ElasticSearch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rabbitmq.com/&quot;&gt;RabbitMQ&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Swift&quot;&gt;objectStorage (S3/Swift)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback on this product, announced as a beta since 3.5.0 is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This product can be executed via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/james-project/blob/master/dockerfiles/run/docker-compose.yml&quot;&gt;docker-compose&lt;/a&gt; or you can follow its &lt;a href=&quot;/server/install/guice-cassandra-rabbitmq-swift.html&quot;&gt;standard installation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-of-support-for-java-8&quot;&gt;End of support for Java 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James 3.5.x is the last release line to support Java 8. From 3.6.0 James will run on a Java Runtime Environment 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;release-changelog&quot;&gt;Release changelog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distributed task management for Distributed James product. This enables several James servers to share a consistent view
of tasks being currently executed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2563 Health check for ElasticSearch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2904 Authentication and SSL support for Cassandra backend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2904 Authentication and SSL support for ElasticSearch backend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3066 Add support alias when sending emails, with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/james-project/blob/master/src/site/markdown/server/manage-webadmin.md#retrieving-the-list-of-allowed-from-headers-for-a-given-user&quot;&gt;“allowed From headers” webadmin endpoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3062 HealthCheck for EventDeadLetters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3058 WebAdmin offline task to correct mailbox inconsistencies on top of Cassandra products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3105 WebAdmin offline task to recompute mailbox counters on top of Cassandra products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3072 Webadmin endpoint to export mailbox backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple changes have been made to enhance Distributed James indexing performance:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use of routing keys to collocate documents per mailbox&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Under some configuration, html was not extracted before document indexing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Removed unnecessary fields from mailbox mapping&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Disable dynamic mapping thanks to a change of the header structure&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2855 Multiple library/plugin/docker images/build tool upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default the cassandra keyspace creation by James is now disabled by default. This allow to have credentials limited to a keyspace. It can be enabled by setting cassandra.keyspace.create=true in the cassandra.properties file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usernames are assumed to be always lower cased. Many users recently complained about mails non received when sending to upper cased local recipients. We decided to simplify the handling of case for local recipients and users by always storing them lower cased.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unhealthy health checks now return HTTP 503 instead of 500, degraded now returns 200 instead of 500. See JAMES-2576.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to fasten JMAP-draft message retrieval upon calls on properties expected to be fast to fetch, we now compute the preview and hasAttachment properties asynchronously and persist them in Cassandra to improve performance. See JAMES-2919.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is now forbidden to create new Usernames with the following set of characters in its local part : &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;(),:; &amp;lt;&amp;gt;@\[]&lt;/code&gt;, as we prefer it to stay simple to handle. However, the read of Usernames already existing with some of those characters is still allowed, to not introduce any breaking change. See JAMES-2950.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linshare blob export configuration and mechanism change. See JAMES-3040.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Differentiation between domain alias and domain mapping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3122 Log4J2 adoption for Spring product. Log file configuration needs to be updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read related &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/james-project/blob/master/upgrade-instructions.md#3.5.0-version&quot;&gt;upgrade instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2828 &amp;amp; JAMES-2929 bugs affecting JDBCMailRepository usage with PostgresSQL thanks to Jörg Thomas &amp;amp; Sergey B&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2936 Creating a mailbox using consecutive delimiter character leads to creation of list of unnamed mailbox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2911 Unable to send mail from James using an SMTP gateway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2944 Inlined attachments should be wrapped in multipart/related by JMAP draft&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2941 Return NO when an IMAP command unexpectedly fails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2943 Deleting auto detected domain should fail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2957 dlp.Dlp matcher should parse emails containing attachments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2958 Limit domain name size to not longer than 255 characters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2939 Prevent mixed case INBOX creation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2903 Rework default LOG4J log file for Spring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2739 fixed browse mails from queue over JMX&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2375 DSNBounce mailet should provide a subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2097 RemoteDelivery: Avoid retrying already succeeded recipients when sendPartial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAILBOX-392 Mailbox name validation upon mailbox creation is stricter: forbid &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&amp;amp;*%&lt;/code&gt; and empty sub-mailboxes names.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2972 Incorrect attribute name in the mailet configuration thanks to jtconsol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2632 JMAP Draft GetMailboxes performance enhancements when retrieving all mailboxes of a user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-2964 Forbid to create User quota/ Domain quota/ Global quota using negative number&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3074 Fixing UidValidity generation, sanitizing of invalid values upon reads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classes marked as deprecated whose removal was planned after 3.4.0 release (See JAMES-2703). This includes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SieveDefaultRepository. Please use SieveFileRepository instead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JDBCRecipientRewriteTable, XMLRecipientRewriteTable, UsersRepositoryAliasingForwarding, JDBCAlias mailets. Please use RecipientRewriteTable mailet instead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JDBCRecipientRewriteTable implementation. Please use JPARecipientRewriteTable instead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;JamesUsersJdbcRepository, DefaultUsersJdbcRepository. Please use JpaUsersRepository instead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MailboxQuotaFixed matcher. Please use IsOverQuota instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UsersFileRepository, which was marked as deprecated for years
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We accordingly removed deprecated methods within UsersRepositoryManagementMBean exposed over JMX (unsetAlias, getAlias, unsetForwardAddress, getForwardAddress). RecipientRewriteTables should be used instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3016 RemoteDelivery now doesn’t enable &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;allow8bitmime&lt;/code&gt; property by default. 
This parameter could cause body content alteration leading to invalid DKIM signatures to be positioned. 
Thanks to Sergey B. for the report. 
More details about the property is at &lt;a href=&quot;https://javaee.github.io/javamail/docs/api/com/sun/mail/smtp/package-summary.html&quot;&gt;java mail doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JAMES-3122 LogEnabled API in Spring product had been removed for Log4J2 adoption for Java 9+ runtime compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-party-softwares&quot;&gt;Third party softwares&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The distributed James server product (relying on Guice, Cassandra, ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ and optionally Swift) now needs at least RabbitMQ 3.8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tika prior 1.24 is subject to multiple CVEs. We recommend the upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 20:16:30 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2020/07/16/james-3.5.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2020/07/16/james-3.5.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Benoit Tellier presents James at ApacheCon Europe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Benoit had the pleasure to present James at the ApacheCon at Berlin: “Gaining control over emails with Apache James”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed him you can see his conference on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zr8qpNkL6U4&quot;&gt;youtube&lt;/a&gt;, or read his &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/linagora-engineering/linagora-representing-james-at-the-apachecon-europe-2019-c6e28b31242a&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 21:16:30 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/apachecon/2019/11/19/apache-con-eu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/apachecon/2019/11/19/apache-con-eu.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>apachecon</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.4.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apache James developers are pleased to announce James server 3.4.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in-memory docker image&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support of AWS S3 as blobstore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebAdmin routes for mapping management (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AddAddressMapping&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AddRegexMapping&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ListMappings&lt;/code&gt;), previously only manageable by CLI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metrics for Deleted Message Vault&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More metrics for BlobStore (new delete &amp;amp; deleteBucket configuration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(experimental) New implementation of the deleted message vault on top of an object store, not relying anymore on a 
repository. This avoids exposing messages via webAdmin. Messages previously stored in the vault will be lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migration to ElasticSearch 6.3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blob export to LinShare&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Native DKIM support for outgoing mails. The mailets from james-jdkim have been included in main James project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deprecated&quot;&gt;Deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zookeeper component. This will be removed after 3.4 release. If you have development skills, and are willing to maintain this component, please reach us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karaf OSGi implementation. It was not compiled nor tested for a year. We didn’t get any feedback about that and we don’t have the resources nor the skills to maintain it any more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 20:16:30 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/09/05/james-3.4.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/09/05/james-3.4.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James `latest` Docker images changes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have decided to change the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; Docker images behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until nowadays, such images were built on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch for each products (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;linagora/james-memory&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;linagora/james-cassandra-rabbitmq-ldap-project&lt;/code&gt;, …).&lt;br /&gt;
This is not the way &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; docker image should be, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.container-solutions.com/docker-latest-confusion&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; is explaining this kind of misunderstood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we decided to follow the global Docker users behaviour which is to clone the &lt;em&gt;latest stable release&lt;/em&gt; as the Docker &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are willing to use a Docker image on top of the master branch, you can use the newly created &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;branch-master&lt;/code&gt; tag,&lt;br /&gt;
which is published on each merge on the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: you should not use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; image in a production deployment, otherwise you are at risk of jumping from one major release to another unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,
Antoine&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:09:47 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/08/30/latest-image-changes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/08/30/latest-image-changes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.3.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apache James developers are pleased to announce James server 3.3.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metrics for BlobStore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Guice product using Cassandra RabbitMQ ElasticSearch, OpenStack Swift and optional LDAP dependency (experimental)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JPA SMTP dockerFile contributed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matzepan&quot;&gt;matzepan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listing healthchecks, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kratostaine&quot;&gt;Madhu Bhat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configuring the ElasticSearch clusterName&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Logging and Metrics now supports Elasticsearch 6 (previously only Elasticsearch 2 was supported)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implementation of the RabbitMQ EventBus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DeadLetter APIs and memory implementation for storing events that failed delivery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RecipientRewriteTable Aliases and associated WebAdmin routes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAILBOX-350 Potential invalid UID &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; MSN mapping upon IMAP COPY&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Possibility to better zoom in Grafana boards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;default ElasticSearch shards &amp;amp; replica configured values&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move &amp;amp; copy batch sizes are now loaded from configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebAdmin ReIndexing API had been reworked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MailboxListener and mailbox event system were reworked. Custom listeners will need to be adapted. Please see Upgrade instuctions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Docker images are now using a JRE instead of a JDK&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replacement of the old mailbox event system with the EventBus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop HBase and JCR components (mailbox and server/data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-party-softwares&quot;&gt;Third party softwares&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tika prior 1.20 is subject to multiple CVEs. We recommend the upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:09:47 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/03/26/james-3.3.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/03/26/james-3.3.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Mime4J 0.8.3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James Mime4J 0.8.2 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release includes the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-270: Using “alternative” as default subtype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-263: decoding encoded words with empty encoded-text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-279: Fixed JavaDoc errors to comply with Java8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-280: Improve exception handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-283: DecoderUtil performance fix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is available as a maven artifact, for instance for mime4j core:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.james&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;apache-mime4j-core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.8.3&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also download the release artifacts &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.apache.org/james/mime4j/0.8.3/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 08:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/03/19/mime4j-0.8.3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2019/03/19/mime4j-0.8.3.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.2.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apache James developers are pleased to announce James server 3.2.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mail filtering configured via the JMAP protocol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebAdmin exposed mail re-indexing tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebAdmin exposed health checks. This includes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Possibility to perform a single healthcheck, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mschnitzler&quot;&gt;mschnitzler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cassandra health checks thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matzepan&quot;&gt;matzepan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IMAP MOVE commend (RFC-6851) On top of JPA. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mschnitzler&quot;&gt;mschnitzler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JPA support for Sieve script storage thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sebast26&quot;&gt;Sebast26&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sieve script upload via the CLI thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matzepan&quot;&gt;matzepan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mailet DOC: Exclude from documentation annotation thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mschnitzler&quot;&gt;mschnitzler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cassandra.pooling.max.queue.size&lt;/strong&gt; configuration option Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matzepan&quot;&gt;matzepan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RecipentDomainI&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;SenderDomainIs&lt;/strong&gt; matchers by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athulyaraj&quot;&gt;athulyaraj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple libraries updates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migration from Cassandra 2 to Cassandra 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mail::getSender was deprecated. Mail::getMaybeSender offers better Null Sender support. Java 8 default API method was used to not break compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deprecated&quot;&gt;Deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HBase and JCR components (mailbox and server/data). This will be removed as part of 3.3.0. If you have development skills, and are willing to maintain these components, please reach us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop partially implemented Kafka distributed events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-party-softwares&quot;&gt;Third party softwares&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SpamAssassin prior 3.4.2 is subject to multiple CVEs. We recommend the upg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 12:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/11/14/james-3.2.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/11/14/james-3.2.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.1.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James server 3.1.0 has been releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce an object store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configurable listeners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MDN (Message Disposition notification) parsing and handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SpamAssassin support with per user reports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search in attachments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Leak Prevention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JPA SMTP Guice product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cassandra migration process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structured logging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RPM packaging (in addition to deb packaging)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegating folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve Mail Repositories handling, including a nice web API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve Mail Queues handling, including a nice web API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve RRT (Recipient Rewrite Table) implementation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quota handling improvements, and in particular users can receive an email when they are near the limit of their quota&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many performances enhancement, in particular on Cassandra backend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 21:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/07/31/james-3.1.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/07/31/james-3.1.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linagora June newsletter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the name of the James team @Linagora I will be presenting you what we did in the past few weeks, and plan to work on in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to work on some specific features to make James easier to adopt for large organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-was-achieved-in-may&quot;&gt;What was achieved in May&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notifications-when-soon-over-quota&quot;&gt;Notifications when soon over quota&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A mail needs to be sent to the user to warn him. This is an attempts to allow clients not implementing quota’s RFCs to still get the warning.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is implemented with mailbox listeners (and not mailets), with event sourcing. We added the interfaces and implementations to achieve this feature in James using event sourcing with events being stored in Cassandra or in memory.
Such a technical solution might be very useful to implement other feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This mailbox listener is optional. We allowed one to register his (potentially custom) mailbox listeners when working with Guice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;searching-user-by-quota-usage&quot;&gt;Searching user by quota usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This would allow an admin to inspect per-user quota usage, via a webadmin interface.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Again, we provided two implementations: a scanning one, which naively enumerates mailboxes to compute occupation, and one where quota occupation is indexed in ElasticSearch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance-enhancements&quot;&gt;Performance enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order to have a very good mail search experience, it is possible to plug Apache Tika as a text extractor into James. We use Tika as an external service that we call with HTTP. When you use this Tika extractor with ElasticSearch indexing, you get a very powerful fulltext search even on complex attachment format like LibreOffice documents.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We did experience slow requests with our Tika server. We contributed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/237&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; which significantly enhanced Tika server performance, and we introduce a cache on James side to reduce calls to tika.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We also worked on improving massive JMAP operation performance (delete a large number of emails).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-we-will-work-on-in-june&quot;&gt;What we will work on in June&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-leak-prevention&quot;&gt;Data Leak Prevention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We should have a matcher applying rules defined by the admin. This matcher will then store suspicious emails in specific mail repository for an admin review.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To implement this, we need to enhance browsing to MailRepository via WebAdmin. We need to allow storing such rules as well as updating them via webadmin. We need finally a mailet storing emails in a repository given its sender domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exporting-a-mail-account&quot;&gt;Exporting a mail account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As an administrator, I should be able to export the content of my mail account. This both allows easier migrations, comply with legal requirements as well as allow some forms of backups.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The chosen format is EMLs in a ZIP format, with the folder structure described in archive meta-data, and specific metadata to ease restoring a James account (flags, etc…). An administrator (via webamin) should be able to download/upload such backups in order to do export/restores mail accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coming-next&quot;&gt;Coming next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along side these features that turns out to be necessary for large organisations, our focus will be on having a distributed
James server. To achieve this, we will propose soon a distributed mail queue based on RabbitMQ.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 11:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/06/06/linagora-june-nl.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/06/06/linagora-june-nl.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Mime4J 0.8.2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James Mime4J 0.8.2 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release solves the following bugs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-267 MIME4J DOM parsing errors on specific formats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-273 Correcting encoder splitting point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following feature were added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-269 Introduce a safe to use, PERMISSIVE configuration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-268 DefaultMessageWriter: expose a convenient &lt;em&gt;asBytes&lt;/em&gt; method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-271 Make possible to define a Content-Type parameter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-272 Implicit DOM builder call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is available as a maven artifact, for instance for mime4j core:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.james&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;apache-mime4j-core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.8.2&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also download the release artifacts &lt;a href=&quot;https://downloads.apache.org/james/mime4j/0.8.2/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 11:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/05/07/mime4j-0.8.2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/05/07/mime4j-0.8.2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
