<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
    Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
    or more contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file
    distributed with this work for additional information
    regarding copyright ownership. The ASF licenses this file
    to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
    "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
    with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
    software distributed under the License is distributed on an
    "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
    KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the
    specific language governing permissions and limitations
    under the License.
-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Website</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://james.apache.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://james.apache.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:17:36 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:17:36 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.1.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James server 3.1.0 has been releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some points we worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce an object store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configurable listeners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MDN (Message Disposition notification) parsing and handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SpamAssassin support with per user reports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search in attachments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Leak Prevention&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JPA SMTP Guice product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cassandra migration process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structured logging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RPM packaging (in addition to deb packaging)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegating folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move to Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve Mail Repositories handling, including a nice web API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve Mail Queues handling, including a nice web API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve RRT (Recipient Rewrite Table) implementation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quota handling improvements, and in particular users can receive an email when they are near the limit of their quota&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many performances enhancement, in particular on Cassandra backend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early adopters can &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 21:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/07/31/james-3.1.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/07/31/james-3.1.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Linagora June newsletter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the name of the James team @Linagora I will be presenting you what we did in the past few weeks, and plan to work on in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to work on some specific features to make James easier to adopt for large organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-was-achieved-in-may&quot;&gt;What was achieved in May&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notifications-when-soon-over-quota&quot;&gt;Notifications when soon over quota&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A mail needs to be sent to the user to warn him. This is an attempts to allow clients not implementing quota’s RFCs to still get the warning.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is implemented with mailbox listeners (and not mailets), with event sourcing. We added the interfaces and implementations to achieve this feature in James using event sourcing with events being stored in Cassandra or in memory.
Such a technical solution might be very useful to implement other feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This mailbox listener is optional. We allowed one to register his (potentially custom) mailbox listeners when working with Guice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;searching-user-by-quota-usage&quot;&gt;Searching user by quota usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This would allow an admin to inspect per-user quota usage, via a webadmin interface.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Again, we provided two implementations: a scanning one, which naively enumerates mailboxes to compute occupation, and one where quota occupation is indexed in ElasticSearch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance-enhancements&quot;&gt;Performance enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order to have a very good mail search experience, it is possible to plug Apache Tika as a text extractor into James. We use Tika as an external service that we call with HTTP. When you use this Tika extractor with ElasticSearch indexing, you get a very powerful fulltext search even on complex attachment format like LibreOffice documents.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We did experience slow requests with our Tika server. We contributed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/237&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; which significantly enhanced Tika server performance, and we introduce a cache on James side to reduce calls to tika.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We also worked on improving massive JMAP operation performance (delete a large number of emails).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-we-will-work-on-in-june&quot;&gt;What we will work on in June&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-leak-prevention&quot;&gt;Data Leak Prevention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We should have a matcher applying rules defined by the admin. This matcher will then store suspicious emails in specific mail repository for an admin review.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To implement this, we need to enhance browsing to MailRepository via WebAdmin. We need to allow storing such rules as well as updating them via webadmin. We need finally a mailet storing emails in a repository given its sender domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exporting-a-mail-account&quot;&gt;Exporting a mail account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As an administrator, I should be able to export the content of my mail account. This both allows easier migrations, comply with legal requirements as well as allow some forms of backups.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The chosen format is EMLs in a ZIP format, with the folder structure described in archive meta-data, and specific metadata to ease restoring a James account (flags, etc…). An administrator (via webamin) should be able to download/upload such backups in order to do export/restores mail accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coming-next&quot;&gt;Coming next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along side these features that turns out to be necessary for large organisations, our focus will be on having a distributed
James server. To achieve this, we will propose soon a distributed mail queue based on RabbitMQ.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 11:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/06/06/linagora-june-nl.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/06/06/linagora-june-nl.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Mime4J 0.8.2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James Mime4J 0.8.2 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release solves the following bugs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-267 MIME4J DOM parsing errors on specific formats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-273 Correcting encoder splitting point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following feature were added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-269 Introduce a safe to use, PERMISSIVE configuration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-268 DefaultMessageWriter: expose a convenient &lt;em&gt;asBytes&lt;/em&gt; method&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-271 Make possible to define a Content-Type parameter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIME4J-272 Implicit DOM builder call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is available as a maven artifact, for instance for mime4j core:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.james&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;apache-mime4j-core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.8.2&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also download the release artifacts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/dist/james/mime4j/0.8.2/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 11:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/05/07/mime4j-0.8.2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/05/07/mime4j-0.8.2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache JAMES joins Google Summer of code 2018 !</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, James developers will propose ideas of Google Summer of Code projects for students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt; is a global program focused on bringing more student developers into open source software development.
Students work with an open source organization on a 3 month programming project during their break from school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gsoc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Summer of code communication image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider it is a dreamed occasion to discover the Apache James project, and get on board in this amazing project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are willing to offer high quality mentoring on high added value, useful tasks. As a student:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🎓  You will discover how Open Source world works. You will exchange with our community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🎓  You will be advised by experienced, long term committers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🎓  You will build technical experience on a mail server.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🎓  And hopefully you will get some code contributions on an Apache project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ideas of applications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;⚒ &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES-1931&quot;&gt;JAMES-1931&lt;/a&gt; We are in need of a WebAdmin User Interface to ease our beloved administrator API. You will need to build an administration website on top of the &lt;strong&gt;webAdmin&lt;/strong&gt; REST API.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;⚒ &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES-1932&quot;&gt;JAMES-1932&lt;/a&gt; James allow to fully customize mail processing. But we miss tools to ease edition and testing of the processing flow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;⚒ &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES-1933&quot;&gt;JAMES-1933&lt;/a&gt; Emails need to be secure. Many protocols like DKIM, SPF and DMARC allow to meet this purpose. However we need more documentation and a DMARC implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;⚒ &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES-2335&quot;&gt;JAMES-2335&lt;/a&gt; James should be a flexible server. We should be able to use custom configuration providers, not only XML files as of today. That is a move toward “clustering done the right way”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we are very open if you want to propose other ideas to us! Come and discuss this on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/apache/james-project&quot;&gt;our gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; or on the issues directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you by advance for your involvement and hope to see you around!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 05:00:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/announcements/2018/02/01/gsoc-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/announcements/2018/02/01/gsoc-2018.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New administration features: manage your queues and your reporitories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An often asked feature for James is the ability to handle the mails, that after some processing,
have landed in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/server/feature-persistence.html&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;, for example /var/mail/error/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brand new webadmin API allows you to handle the content of these repositories, see the documentation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://james.apache.org/server/manage-webadmin.html&quot;&gt;manage-webadmin&lt;/a&gt;.
It allows you to list the repositories, their content, but also to reprocess one or several mails in the processor and queue
of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh! And bonus, now you can forget this non scalable file repository and use the brand new Cassandra repository!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the same documentation page you will also find the new mail queue management API, done to list queued mails, remove some
of them regarding different criteria, but also flush delayed mails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the work on these already usable features is done, but we still have some ideas for related improvements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20JAMES%20AND%20resolution%20%3D%20Unresolved%20AND%20labels%20in%20(feature)%20AND%20component%20%20in%20(Queue%2C%20%22MailStore%20%26%20MailRepository%22)%20AND%20type%20in%20(Improvement)&quot;&gt;Contributions&lt;/a&gt; are welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 05:00:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/01/26/admin-features.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2018/01/26/admin-features.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security release: Apache James server 3.0.1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apache James PMCs are glad to announce you the release
version 3.0.1 of Apache James server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It fixes vulnerability described in CVE-2017-12628. The JMX server, also
used by the command line client is exposed to a java de-serialization
issue, and thus can be used to execute arbitrary commands. As James
exposes JMX socket by default only on local-host, this vulnerability can
only be used for privilege escalation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release 3.0.1 upgrades the incriminated library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that you can take additional defensive steps in order to mitigate this vulnerability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that you restrict the access to JMX only on local-host&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that you are using a recent Java Run-time Environment. For instance OpenJDK 8 u111 is vulnerable but OpenJDK 8 u 141 is not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can additionally run James in a container to limit damages of potential exploits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And of course upgrade to the newest 3.0.1 version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about Java deserialization &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sourceclear.com/blog/Commons-Collections-Deserialization-Vulnerability-Research-Findings/&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 05:00:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/20/james-3.0.1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/20/james-3.0.1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacktoberfest: contribute to James</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The James project joins the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;Hactoberfest&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieve available issues on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/linagora/james-project/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3AHacktoberfest&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hactoberfest.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hacktoberfest logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributions are diversified and feature some core James components like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional mailet/matcher contributions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional Command Line options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional WebAdmin functionality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JPA Mailbox missing components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 21:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/03/Hacktoberfest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/03/Hacktoberfest.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog post: Easy and secure James installation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@thibaut.sautereau/installing-james-3-0-with-spf-verification-421b26b92f11&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thithib&quot;&gt;Thibaut&lt;/a&gt; explains us how to easily set up a James server on a personal domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gives hints about DNS configuration, SSL configuration, James configuration, and SPF configuration. All those
features explained with working examples!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 21:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/03/BlogPostInstallingJames.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/10/03/BlogPostInstallingJames.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James Server 3.0.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James server 3.0.0 has been released !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;http://james.apache.org/download.cgi#Apache_James_Server&quot;&gt;download it&lt;/a&gt;, any issue can be reported on our issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/JAMES&quot;&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 21:13:22 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/07/20/james-3.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/07/20/james-3.0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apache James JSieve 0.7</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;James JSieve 0.7 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is available as a maven artifact, for instance for jsieve core:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.james&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;apache-jsieve-core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.7&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release solves issues with folded encoded header matching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also adds an additional DiscardAction to make discarding emails explicit for the calling code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/06/23/jsieve-0.7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://james.apache.org/james/update/2017/06/23/jsieve-0.7.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>james</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
